A Guide to the Bond referendum records of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1977
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Bond referendum records of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1977
The Library of Virginia
39372
3.5 cu. ft. (10 boxes)
Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 39372 transferred by the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 27 March 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth has evolved from early colonial times when there existed a Secretary of the Colony. Thomas Nelson held the position of the first Secretary of Virginia in 1776. Early Secretaries were elected by the public. An Act of the General Assembly in 1920 changed the election to a joint vote of the General Assembly. In a 1930 Act the duties of the Secretary were redefined with the Secretary of the Commonwealth serving as the ex officio secretary of the Governor, as custodian of many official State records, and as keeper of the Greater and Lesser Seals of the Commonwealth. The office of the Secretary has gradually acquired other functions, such as: service of out-of-state civil process; appointment and regulation of notaries public; and registration and oversight of lobbyists. The Office became a gubernational appointment subsequent to a 1958 Act of the Assembly. The Secretary of the Commonwealth is under the jurisdiction of the Governor's Office.
The Secretary is appointed by the Governor for a term of four years. Currently the Secretary of the Commonwealth is responsible for gubernatorial appointments, clemency and restoration of civil rights requests and extraditions. Additional activities include: serving as ex officio Secretary to the Governor; serving as keeper of the seals of the Commonwealth; compiling and publishing the annual Blue Book; commissioning and regulating notary publics, including the publication of a Notary Handbook and conduct of disciplinary hearings; promulgating the lobbying disclosure requirements, registration of lobbyists, and recording of lobbying reports; servicing the civil process of out-of-state defendants and other parties; and authenticating and certifying the records of the courts and of any state agency.
Scope and Content
Bond referendum records, 1977, is housed in 10 boxes and contains correspondence, articles, newsclippings, publications, speeches, and other material related to a bond issue for educational institutions, correctional facilities, mental health facilities, park and recreation facilities and port facilities. The majority of these records are related to bonds for the purpose of raising funds to pay for capital projects at state-supported colleges, universities, museums and other educational facilities. Also includes permission forms from institutions of higher education to talk to students about the bond referendum that note conditions, approvals and denials; bond issue background and support / opposition information; promotional packets.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the original order.
Contents List
- Bond referendum records, 1977.
  - Virginians for Bonds - Packets (District 1), 1977. (Box 1)
  - Virginians for Bonds - Packets (District 2), 1977. (Box 1)
  - Virginians for Bonds - Packets (District 3), 1977. (Box 1)
  - Virginians for Bonds - Packets (District 4), 1977. (Box 1)
  - Virginians for Bonds - Packets (District 5), 1977. (Box 1)
  - Virginians for Bonds - Packets (District 6), 1977. (Box 1)
  - Virginians for Bonds - Packets (District 8), 1977. (Box 1)
  - Virginians for Bonds - Packets (District 10), 1977. (Box 1)
  - James Madison University, 1977. (Box 2)
  - George Mason University, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Longwood College, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Mary Washington College, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Old Dominion University, 1977. (Box 2)
  - University of Virginia, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Military Institute, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1977. (Box 2)
  - State Board of Community Colleges, 1977. (Box 2)
  - College of William and Mary, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Boards of Visitors, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Students, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education, 1977. (Box 3)
  - Ports, 1977. (Box 3)
  - General Assembly - Letters of support, 1977. (Box 3)
  - General Assembly - Mailings, 1977. (Box 3)
  - General Assembly - Meeting, 1977 May 7. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Taxpayer Association, 1977. (Box 3)
  - Citizen correspondence, 1977. (Box 3)
  - Fairfax County Taxpayers Alliance, 1977. (Box 3)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Speaker requests, 1977. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Speaker requests filled, 1977. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Speaker's Bureau volunteers, 1977. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Quotes from speeches by the Governor, 1977. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Council of Visitors, 1977 Sept 26. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Salem-Roanoke Civic Center, 1977 Oct 4. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Woodstock, 1977 Oct 5. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - UVA Legal Forum, 1977 Oct 13. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Winchester, 1977 Oct 13. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Petersburg Kiwanis, 1977 Oct 18. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Commonwealth Women's Club, 1977 Oct 19. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Norfolk Scope, 1977 Oct 26. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Public Affairs Group meeting, 1977 June 17. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Meeting with College Rectors, 1977 June 27. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Virginia Pork Festival (Emporia), 1977 June 8. (Box 4)
  - Governor speaking engagements - Virginia Chicken Festival (Crewe), 1977 June 15. (Box 4)
  - Bond program newsclippings, 1977. (Box 5)
  - Press releases, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Media, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Adverstising agencies, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Candidate mailings, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Congressional Delegation, 1977. (Box 6)
  - News conferences, 1977. (Box 6)
  - TV and radio list, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Public information officers, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Newspaper mailing lists, 1977. (Box 6)
  - News editor luncheon, 1977. (Box 6)
  - TV and radio luncheon, 1977. (Box 6)
  - VPI Extension Service, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous organizations, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Preliminary information mailing, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Permissions for District 1 - Christopher Newport University, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 1 - Thomas Nelson Community College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 1 - William and Mary, College of, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 2 - Old Dominion University, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 2 - Norfolk State College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 2 - Tidewater Community College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 3 - Virginia Commonwealth University, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 5 - Longwood College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 5 - Patrick Henry Community College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 5 - Southside Virginia Community College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 5 - Danville Community College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 6 - Virginia Military Institute, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 7 - James Madison University, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 7 - Mary Washington College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 7 - Piedmont Virginia Community College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 7 - Univesity of Virginia, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 8 - George Mason University, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 8 - Northern Virginia Community College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 9 - Radford College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 9 - Clinch Valley College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 9 - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Permissions for District 10 - Northern Virginia Community College, 1977. (Box 7)
  - Fact Book on Higher Education in the South 1968. (Box 8)
  - Fact Book on Higher Education in the South, 1971-1972. (Box 8)
  - Fact Book on Higher Education in the South, 1975-1976. (Box 8)
  - Students for Bonds - Coordinators, 1977. (Box 8)
  - Students for Bonds - Kits, 1977. (Box 8)
  - Students for Bonds - Organization, 1977. (Box 8)
  - Captital projects by districts, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Justification for student campaigns, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Absentee ballots, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Bond information, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Capital outlay requests, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Bond issue financing, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Fact sheets, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Operating costs for bond project, 1977. (Box 9)
  - State's economic and financial status, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Legislative authorization, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Voter registration, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Poll data, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Corrections, 1977. (Box 9)
  - State ports, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Mental health, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Academy of Family Physicians, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Association of Contractors, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Association of Counties, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Bond Club of Virginia, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Commissioners of Revenue Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Commonwealth Women's Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Consulting Engineers Council of Virginia, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Council of State Legislation, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Fairfax Chamber of Commerce, 1977. (Box 10)
  - League of Women Voters, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Mary Washington Alumni Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Federation of Chapters of the National Association of Retired Federal Employees, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Old Dominion Bar Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Republican Party of Virginia, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Tidwater Builders Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Agribusiness Council, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Automobile Dealers Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Bankers Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Bar Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Chamber of Commerce, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Education Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Farm Bureau, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Federation of Womens Clubs, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Florist Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Extension Homemakers Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Forestry Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Food Dealers Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Home Economists Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Institute of Chemists, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Mortgage Bankers Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Pharmaceutical Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Poultry Federation, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Association of Professors, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Retail Merchants Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Virginia School Superintendents Association, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Citizen support, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Suggested resolution, 1977. (Box 10)
  - State boards and commissions, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Association mailing information, 1977. (Box 10)
  - Endorsements received, 1977. (Box 10)